Guide to the Eleanor Lansing Dulles papers, 1867-1993 MS2217
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Personal, 1904-1993; 1936-1990; Series 1; 4.75 Linear Feet
  Personal correspondence falls under this series. General personal correspondence has been arranged chronologically, with undated correspondence grouped at the end of the second folder. Dulles kept some correspondence grouped together according to sender or topic. This correspondence pertains mainly to her children, David and Ann, and to her husband, philologist David S. Blondheim. This arrangement has been retained by the archivist, and letters within these original groupings have been arranged chronologically. A personal file of her brother, Allen Dulles, is included here, because it consists mainly of correspondence between the siblings.
  A small amount of material pertaining to Eleanor Lansing Dulles' education at Wykeham Rise School, Bryn Mawr, and Radcliffe is included in this series.
  Dulles' will and that of her husband are contained in Series 1, as well as correspondence, maps, and notes related to her homes and estate.
  Images of Dulles and of her immediate family, friends, home, and personal travel are found in Series 1. Photographs, photographic negatives, and slides are included and date between 1918 and 1989, with the bulk of the images dating between 1923 and 1985. The photographs and negatives are predominately of her children, David and Ann, but also include images of her husband, David S. Blondheim, her parents, and her siblings. The slides were taken mainly at her homes in Washington, DC, Virginia, and Henderson Harbor in New York in the 1950s. A turn-of-the-twentieth-century guestbook/photo album from the Dulles family home, Linden Lodge, in New York is found in this series, and contains candid photographs and signatures of important members of the Dulles family, including Robert Lansing, John Foster Dulles, and Allen Welsh Dulles.
  Eleanor Lansing Dulles collected many postcards throughout her world travels, and these postcards are arranged alphabetically by destination in Series 1. Of particular note are postcards collected by Dulles in France immediately following World War I. These depict ruined buildings in Reims and Verdun.
  Miscellaneous memorabilia collected by Dulles and found among her papers are included in this series. These include a baby curl, (possibly her son, David's), portions of her stamp collection, prints of watercolor renderings of Berlin scenes, a wooden souvenir wall hanging from Berlin, and an ornately-decorated silver book cover with engraved initials.
  - Ann Dulles' Wedding, 1962; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appointment Books, 1936; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointment Books, 1937; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Books, 1937; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Books, 1948; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Appointment Books, 1958; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appointment Books, circa 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Books, 1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Biographical Information, 1944-1967; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Calling Cards and Stationary, undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ceremonies and Special Events, 10/14/1990-05/03/1992; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clippings--Biographical, 1971-1980; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clubs and Organizations--American-Austrian Society, 1989-1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clubs and Organizations--American Economic Association, 12/26/1951; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Clubs and Organizations--American Foreign Service Association, 09/1983-1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Association Island Recreational Corporation, Henderson Harbor, 08/24/1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Clubs and Organizations--City Tavern Association, 1961; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Cosmopolitan Club, 1936-1979; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Cosmopolitan Club, 1980-1986; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Cosmopolitan Club, 1986-1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Cosmopolitan Club, 01/08/1991-1992; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Diplomatic and Consular Officers, Retired (DACOR), 1969-1990; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Henderson Harbor Yacht Club, 1974-1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clubs and Organizations--International Club of Washington, 1966-1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clubs and Organizations--PEN, 11/1975; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clubs and Organizations--Youth for Understanding, 1971-1976; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Contacts--Address Books, 1910-1952; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Contacts--Address Books, 1965-1966 and undated; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Contacts--Business Cards, undated; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Contacts--Card File, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contacts--Directory, undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Contacts--Guestbook, 1982; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Contacts--Honore Marcel Catudal, Jr., 1969-1978; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence [1/2], 11/21/1908-06/28/1984; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence [2/2], 03/19/1985-08/1992 and undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence--Allen Dulles' Personal File for Eleanor Lansing Dulles, 1945-1950; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence--David S. Blondheim, 12/31/1931-01/11/1932; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--Work of David S. Blondheim, 1934; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--David and Ann Dulles in School in Switzerland, 01/04/1945-06/23/1946; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Education--Bryn Mawr, undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Education--Radcliffe, Diploma, 06/23/1926; Series 1 (Flat box 4, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Education--Wykeham Rise School, Washington, Connecticut, Diploma, 06/13/1913; Series 1 (Flat box 4, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Estates and Wills, 1934-1953; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Houses, 1937-1959 and undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lock of hair, David Dulles baby curl?, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, 1963; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, 1965; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, 1966; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, 1967; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Interview, Columbia Univeristy--Transcript, 1978; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University Oral History Collection Catalog, circa 1984; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Images of Eleanor Lansing Dulles [1/2], circa 1918-1969; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Images of Eleanor Lansing Dulles [2/2], 1970-1989 and undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photogtaphs and Negatives--Dulles and unidentified man framed photograph, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 5, Item 12)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Family [1/2], circa 1923-1947; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Family [2/2], circa 1923-1947; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, Negatives, and Slides--Family, 1950-1985 and undated; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Family, Friends, Home, and Travel, 1906-1986; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and Negatives--Gstaad Switzerland, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photograph -- Tank opens fire on East Berlin uprising, 1953 June 17; Series 1 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 5)
    General
    Written on back of image "Two German workers defy one of the tanks which opened fire on rioters in the East sector of Berlin on June 17, 1953 killing several hundred."
  - Negatives--Family, 1935-1941; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Slides--Christmas, 1958; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Slides--Foggy Bottom and Thanksgiving, 1958; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Slides--Haiti, 03/1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Slides--Henderson Harbor, 08/1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Slides--Henderson Harbor, 09/1960; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Slides--House in Virginia, circa 1950s; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Slides--House and Travel, 05/1957; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Slides--Sailing, Linden Lodge, Henderson Harbor, John Foster Dulles at airport, 1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Slides--Six Town Point Island, Lake Ontario, 1958; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - David Dulles Baby Photo Album, circa 1934; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Guestbook/Photo Album--Linden Lodge, 1904-1915; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Postcards-Afghanistan, Turkey, and Palestine, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Postcards-Africa, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Postcards-Antigua and Haiti, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Postcards-Austria, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Postcards-Bahamas, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Postcards-Bermuda, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Postcards-Brazil, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Postcards-Cambodia and Philippines, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Postcards-China and Japan, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Postcards-Canada, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Postcards-Denmark, Finland, and Netherlands, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Postcards-Fiji, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Postcards-France and Belgium, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Postcards-Germany, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Postcards-Germany, Berlin, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Postcards-Greece and Macedonia, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Postcards-Italy, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Postcards-Switzerland, undated; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Postcards-United Kingdom, undated; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Postcards-United States, undated; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Postcards-United States, Henderson Harbor, New York, undated; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Poster, Bryn Mawr Speech, "Crises in Foreign Policy", 10/25/1983; Series 1 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Engraving -- Back of the State House, Philadelphia, from the Atwater Kent Museum's Collections, undated; Series 1 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 6)
    Engraved and published by W. Birch and Sons. Sold by R. Campbell and Co. No 50 Chesnut Street Philadelphia 1799
  - Prints of Watercolor Renderings of Berlin Scenes, circa 1950-1969; Series 1 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 3, Oversize-folder 4)
  - Silver Book Cover with Engraved Initials, undated; Series 1; Front board only of book cover. Possibly Bible cover. Some red rot present in remaining leather edges. (Flat box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stamp Collection, 1947-1976; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4, Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Wooden Berlin Souvenir Wall Hanging, undated; Series 1 (Box SHARED Box 20, Box 1, Folder 1)
- Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees, 1935-1993; 1975-1993; Series 2; 1 Linear Feet
  Arranged alphabetically according to the institution or organization granting the award or degree.
  Series 2 contains certificates, diplomas, correspondence, invitations, and photographs related to awards and honorary degrees received by Eleanor Lansing Dulles. Material in this series ranges in date from 1935 to 1993, with the majority of the material dating between 1975 and 1993.
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees, 1959-1991; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Aite Nazarethkirche Berlin-Wedding coin, 1976; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 11)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--The American Woman commemorative U.S. postage stamp, 1960; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Berlin, Free University, Medical Center Dedication, 10/09/1968; Series 2 (Flat box 4, Volume 3)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Berlin Free University, Political Science Faculty, 02/23/1957; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 6, Flat box 4, Oversize-folder 2)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Bonn, Honorary Professorship, Certificate and Tassle, 03/13/1985; Series 2 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Bryn Mawr, circa 1970; Series 2 (Map-folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Bryn Mawr, circa 1970; Series 2 (Map-folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees-- Bryn Mawr College Citation for Distinguished Service, 1967; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 5)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Clarkson College, 1979; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Clarkson College, Photo Album, 07/09/1979; Series 2 (Flat box 4, Volume 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Collegii Westernensis, 1957; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 3)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Duke University, 1965; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 2)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Eisenhower silver jubilee coin, 1953; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 7)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Ernst Reuter Commemorative Plaque (Certificate), 10/21/1959; Series 2 (Flat box 4, Volume 2)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Federation of German-American Clubs, General Lucius D. Clay Medal (certificate), 05/05/1985; Series 2 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Frankfurt Nikolai-Kirche coin, undated; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 9)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees-- The Graduate School of Arts and Sciences of Harvard University Centennial Medal certificate, 1991; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 6)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Konrad Adenauer Zum Gedenken coin, 1967; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 10)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Mount Vernon College, 1975-1993; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees-- Mount Holyoke, 1962; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 4)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Phi Beta Kappa, 05/16/1935; Series 2 (Flat box 3, Oversize-folder 1)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Solidaritat mit der drittenwelt coin, 1982; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Item 8)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Verleihungsurkunde--Das grosse verdienstkreuz, 1962; Series 2 (Flat box 5, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, Awards, and Honorary Degrees--Wilson College, Series 2 (Flat box 4, Oversize-folder 1)
- Writing and Research, 1917-1991; 1968-1985; Series 3; 4.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains material related to Eleanor Lansing Dulles' published and unpublished work from conception to production to promotion. Material in this series is limited to writing and research conducted independently by Eleanor, and not for an employer. It ranges in date from 1917 to 1991, with the bulk of the material dating between 1968 and 1985. Included in this series are research materials such as clippings, articles, and reports; notes and notebooks; manuscripts; correspondence; page proofs; promotional material; and published articles and pamphlets by Eleanor Lansing Dulles. The correspondence in this series relates primarily to the publication of Dulles' work, including acceptance and rejection letters from publishers. The content of the notes and notebooks range from complete thoughts to fragmentary jottings and lists. This series includes mainly works of non-fiction, with the exception of some poetry written by Eleanor in her youth.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Outlines, 10/10/1969-11/06/1980; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Table of Contents and Manuscript [1/3], 1973-1974; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Manuscript [2/3], 1976-1988; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Manuscript [3/3], 1977-1985; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Appendix, 1974 and undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Correspondence, 07/06/1973-09/21/1975; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "Acheson and Dulles"--Funding, Earhart Foundation Fellowship, 06/07/1973-11/19/1980; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "American Foreign Policy in the Making"--Promotion, 03/1968; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ansprachen..., 1957; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Pamphlets, 1935-1990; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Bank for International Settlements at Work", 1932; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Berlin, Four-Power Negotiations--Probable Results"--Manuscript, 11/06/1970; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "Berlin: The Wall is Not Forever"--Promotion, 1967; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "The Brain"--Manuscript, 1978; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Bryn Mawr Fellowship, 1919; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [1/16], 1975; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [2/16], 1976 and undated; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [3/16], 1977; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [4/16], 1977; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [5/16], 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [6/16], 1978; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [7/16], 1979; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [8/16], 1979; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [9/16], 1980; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [10/16], 1980; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [11/16], 1980; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [12/16], 1980; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [13/16], undated; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [14/16], undated; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [15/16], undated; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Draft [16/16], undated; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Notes, 1976; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Chances of a Lifetime"--Photograph Captions, 10/10/1979; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Chronology of Events, 1945-1965", 04/1969; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Chronology of Events", 04/25/1969; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Clippings and Reports, 1920-1991 and undated; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 02/12/1937-04/23/1981 and undated; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Depression and Reconstruction", 12/06/1935; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "L'Europe Nouvelle" Issues, 1925-1929; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Export-Import Bank of Washington, 1944; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Foreign Policy in Midcentury"--Draft, 1980-1990; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Foreign Policy in Midcentury"--Notes and Draft of Chapter 1, 09/30/1982; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "French Franc"--Clipping, 1925-11/02/1929; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Hier ist Eleanor"--Promotional Tour, Germany, November 1982, 06/29/1982-12/20/1982; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "John Foster Dulles: The Image and the Man"--Notes and Drafts, 01/1984-09/27/1984; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "John Foster Dulles: The Image and the Man"--Outline and Draft, 06/10/1984-09/27/1984 and undated; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - "In Remembrance of Things Past: Foster and Janet Dulles"--Proof, 1973; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "Kennedy, Khruschev and Berlin" by John C. Ausland--Manuscript, undated; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "The Lies of History"--Notes and Drafts, 11/1983-01/1984; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1930-1972; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Miscellaneous Topics/Reminders" [Index Cards], undated; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks [1/14], 1929-1931; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks [2/14], 1935-1936; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks [3/14], 1936; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks [4/14], 05/1961; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks [5/14], 1965; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks [6/14], 1971; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks [7/14], 1980; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks [8/14], 1980; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks [9/14], 1980; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks [10/14], 1981; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks [11/14], 08/1981; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks [12/14], 1982; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks [13/14], 04/1985-05/1985; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks [14/14], undated; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "One Germany or Two"--Review, 12/1974; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Poetry, 02/06/1917-01/19/1921; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Submissions, Correspondence, 1977-1985; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Verdienstordens de Bundesrepublik Deutschland", 1951; Series 3 (Flat box 5, Folder 3)
- Employment, 05/1919-1978; 1937-1978; Series 4; 2 Linear Feet
  Series 4 is comprised of material pertaining to Eleanor Lansing Dulles' employment. The series includes correspondence, clippings, reports, publications, brochures, photographs and photographic negatives, scrapbooks, and souvenirs. The material in this series is related to Dulles' work for the American Friends Service during World War I, her economic work for Herbert Hoover in London, for the United States Social Security Board, for the United States Department of State (including the Board for Economic Warfare and Division on Postwar Planning, the German Austrian Division, the Office of German Affairs, the Office of Intelligence and Research, and later consulting work), for Duke University, for the Center for Strategic [and International] Studies at Georgetown University, and the for the Hoover Institution at Stanford University. Documents in Series 3 date between 1919 and 1978, with the majority dating between 1937 and 1978.
  Of particular note are photographs and negatives taken by Eleanor Lansing Dulles circa 1947-1948 depicting scenes in Allied-occupied Austria. The photographs were taken during Eleanor's work as a financial attaché for the United States government, and show Austrian street scenes and people, border check-points, and soldiers. (Box 21, Folders 1-3).
  This series also contains a scrapbook presented to Eleanor during her work for the German Office between 1955 and 1956 containing photographs and hand-painted maps pertaining to a Catholic youth program "Ferienaktion" at Burg Feuerstein in Bavaria. The photographs include images of a youth rally, a camp, dining and recreation facilities, and people flying an airplane named "Ferienaktion." (Box 21, Folder 7).
  Materials documenting the building of Congress Hall (now known as Haus der Kulturen der Welt) in Berlin are found within this series. Eleanor Lansing Dulles played a prominent role in building this important cultural center for the city. At the time that it was built, the building was often referred to as "Frau Dulles' Hut."
  Also of note are an itinerary, photographs, and map received by Eleanor Lansing Dulles as an employee of the Office of Intelligence and Research during a trip with Radio Free Europe in 1960 to the 11th Armored Calvary base in Munich, Germany. The materials provide an interesting picture of border operations in Germany during the Cold War. (Box 22, Folder 2).
  Arranged chronologically by professional position.
  - Relief work in France, 05/1919; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 4)